# **Steve Westhoff**

steve.westhoff38@gmail.com 614-905-0340 Beavercreek, OH Portfolio: stevewesthoff.com

#### **Professional Summary:**

I am a highly capable programmer, technical scripter, and game designer. Have worked independently, and with a team, to successfully plan, coordinate, implement, and develop content and technical systems. An easy-going, positive, and goal-driven person who strives to create the highest quality work. Resourceful professional with experience in designing and scripting content and technical systems in visual and text-based languages, have analyzed, recommended, and tested editor tools improvements. I wrote design documents and scripted instructional web pages as well as evaluated and written reports on content quality and technical systems effectiveness. I have certifications in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, and game scripting. Currently I'm programming ETL interfaces in PL/SQL, Web Services and automated Tools in Java, and am also designing and programming a Unity game in C#.

### **Career Competency Highlights:**

"Steve is one of the stronger developers on the team and is always going above and beyond to expand his knowledge even further... and has even begun to pick up on several areas of DBA expertise. He is always willing to take on any new challenges and is an extremely exceptional independent worker. I know I can depend on him when we face issues occurring in production. He has saved literally hundreds of hours. Steve also delivers exceptional code fixes, scripts, and documentation, ensuring that we meet our SLA's with his quality work. It's wonderful to work with such an independent, trustworthy, and exceptional employee."

~ Kara Donaldson, Operations Support Manager

"Steve is one of the best technical designers and scripters I've worked with. He was stuck with a set of rough tasks and managed to master them. His work was far above what I could have hoped for and he handled numerous difficult issues with a great attitude and work ethic. I would have him on any team I'm part of."

~ Bill Sullivan, Senior Designer

"Any tasks assigned to Steve were always handled efficiently and he often went the extra mile, improving upon the initial design...offering solutions on how to get the same or better results. I often felt that his work was well above his level, allowing me to assign him the same tasks I would a much more senior designer and expect great results." ~ Nik Johansson, Senior Designer

#### **Work Experience:**

Single Step Games: September 2016 – Present

Owner/Programmer/Designer

• Designing, programming, and publishing a VR game for the HTC Vive, Occulus Touch, and Playstation VR.

Accenture: May 2013 – September 2016

Software Development Senior Analyst (Interface Developer, M&O Team)

- Programmed ETL Interfaces in PL/SQL and Web Services in Java
- Programmed automated reporting tools in Java and SQL, saving \$135,000 per year
- Wrote technical design documents and mapped data interfaces
- Optimized a complex web service, reducing the response time by 87%
- Reduced batch run time across five procedures from 11 hours down to 2 hours

Disney Interactive - Junction Point Studio: June 2011 - March 2013 Associate Game Designer (Technical Design)

· Designed, scripted, and maintained technical systems and prefabs in Lua

## **Steve Westhoff**

steve.westhoff38@gmail.com 614-905-0340 Beavercreek, OH

Portfolio: stevewesthoff.com

- Programmed, wrote, and maintained instructional tutorial web pages on Confluence
- Orchestrated and validated improvements to custom tools for Gamebryo's Scene Designer
- Provided technical support to the content designers and outsourced designers, and provided design support to programmers
- Fixed and polished outsourced 2D levels and in-house 3D levels
- Created and supported the Build Verification Test map and instructions

#### Sony Online Entertainment: August 2009 - March 2011

Associate Game Designer (Content Design)

- Designed and scripted gameplay encounters for interior and exterior settings
- Scripted NPC combat abilities (attacks) and A.I. strategies
- Designed and scripted several boss fight encounters using Unreal Editor
- Designed and implemented quest setups, and created in-game cinematics
- Helped streamline the voice over implementation process

#### Whirled World Studios

Designer/Producer

: June 2009 - May 2010

- Published Pinwheel Puzzler for the iPhone
- Authored an award-winning design document
- Designed over 50 Pinwheel puzzle levels
- Coordinated with artist and programmer to create the game mechanics, game modes, UI, and award system
- Designed 30 Cubis puzzle levels as Fresh Games contractor
- Implemented and balanced the Cubis cube queue for playability, fun, and flow

#### Heatwave Interactive: February 2009 - June 2009

#### Design Intern

- Wrote several design concepts, pitches, and game mechanics documents
- Researched and wrote several reports on potential competitor products for three new cross-media intellectual properties
- Designed and programmed a mini-game prototype using C# in Unity

#### **Education:**

Accenture - Application Delivery Fundamentals 2.0: Java

2013

W3Schools.com - Certificates: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript

2013

Austin Community College, Austin, TX - Certificates, 4.0 GPA: Game Scripting, Level Design

Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA - Bachelor of Science, Cum Laude: Psychology

2004

#### **Programming Languages:**

Proficiency: PL/SQL, Java, C#, Lua, Kismet, True Basic Certified: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript

#### **Computer Skills:**

Microsoft Office: Word, Visio, PowerPoint, Excel, and Outlook Perforce (P4V), Rational Team Concert (RTC), Confluence

# **Steve Westhoff**

steve.westhoff38@gmail.com 614-905-0340 Beavercreek, OH Portfolio: stevewesthoff.com

Eclipse, Oracle WebLogic, SoapUI, Oracle SQL Developer

## **Credits and Awards:**

Accenture Celebrates Excellence (ACE) "Alchemist" Award - Accenture	
2015	
Going the Extra Mile (GEM) Award - Accenture	2015
Design credit - Epic Mickey 2: The Power of Two	2012
Level Design credit - Cubis Creatures	2012
Design credit - DC Universe Online	
2011	
Design and Production credits - Pinwheel Puzzler	2009
1st Place - Game Design Contest, Austin Community College	2008
Student of the Year - Distributive Education Clubs of America	2000